Register of the Walter Henry Judd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CHINA FILE, 1922-1984 (Box 157-201)
  - Politics and government
    - Republic of China
      - Kuomintang-Communist relations, 1939-1949 (Box-folder 187: 4)
        Reports, statements (Chiang Kai-shek), resolutions, pamphlets, clippings, press releases, newsletters, and an executive order. Includes material relating to the New Fourth Army during the Sino-Japanese conflict, as well as Communist Party documents.
    - People's Republic of China, 1949-1981 (Box-folder 187: 5)
      Printed articles, speeches, pamphlets, newsletters, and reports.
  - Prisoners, 1949-1971 (Box-folder 187: 6)
    Clippings, report, testimony transcript, notes, printed articles, and correspondence (including the State Department and William Knowland). Includes material relating to Korean and Vietnam War prisoners, missionaries, and the case of Angus Ward.
  - Refugees and relief efforts, 1944-1979 (Box-folder 188: 1)
    Printed material, clippings, a speech (George C. Marshall), correspondence (including the Red Cross), and miscellany. Most of the material on this topic is organized under specific agencies.
  - Russia, relations with, 1928-1975 (Box-folder 188: 2-3)
    Correspondence, serial issues, clippings, press releases, book reviews, reports, notes, newsletters, printed articles, and resolutions.
  - Sun Yat-sen Group, 1930-1948 (Box-folder 188: 4)
    Primarily typescript copies of correspondence (including Walter Lippmann), printed material, and writings of Maurice William and others. Includes material relating to Sun Yat-sen, Russia, Chinese and American communists, and the Spanish Civil War.
  - Taiwan
    - General
      Speeches (including George K.C. Yeh, David Rowe, James C.H. Shen, Hu Shih, and Hollington Tong), reports, clippings, pamphlets, printed articles, press releases, newsletters ( Free China Weekly), flyer, and form letters (including H.H. K'ung).
      - 1949-1954 (Box-folder 188: 5)
      - 1955-1980 (Box-folder 189: 1-3)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1981 (Box-folder 189: 4)
        Includes George K.C. Yeh, William Knowland, and ICA and Taiwanese officials. See also: General/Correspondence/General/Chinese government.
    - Agriculture and land reform, 1950-1980 (Box-folder 189: 5)
      Reports, cover letter, pamphlets, clippings, and press releases.
    - Economics, commerce and industry, 1958-1980 (Box-folder 189: 6)
      Reports with cover letters, clippings, printed articles, press release, and memorandum.
    - Mow-Hsiang case, 1948-1952 (Box-folder 190: 1)
      Reports, press releases, statements (including a joint statement with supporting material by Peter T.K. Pee and Chen Chih-mai), clippings, legal documents and correspondence (including Chiang Kai-shek and Madame Chiang). Relates to charges of corruption made by and against General P.T. Mow (Mao Pang-chu) and Colonel Hsiang Ve-shuen.
    - Wu, K.C., 1953-1955 (Box-folder 190: 2)
      Interview, printed material, and correspondence (including Dwight Eisenhower, Frances Bolton, Charles M. Cooke, George K.C. Yeh, and Chen Chih-mai).
  - Teng Hsiao-ping, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 190: 3)
    Newsletters, clippings, and a pamphlet. Includes criticism of Teng by Hua Kuo-feng.
  - Tibet
    - General, 1949-1984 (Box-folder 190: 4)
    - American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees
      - Non-printed material
        Speech, reports, correspondence, memoranda, agenda and minutes, budgets, and press releases. Includes letters from William O. Douglas, Lowell Thomas, Jay Lovestone, Kenneth Keating, and Jawaharlal Nehru.
        - 1959-1960 (Box-folder 190: 5-7)
        - 1961-1966 (Box-folder 191: 1-4)
        - 1967-1973 (Box-folder 192: 1)
      - Printed material, 1959-1967 (Box-folder 192: 2)
        Booklets, newsletters, reports, clippings, speeches, and resolutions.
      - Trip material, 1963 December and 1965 January (Box-folder 192: 3)
        Notes, reports, letter, and a statement relating to Dr. Judd's trips to India and his meetings with the Dalai Lama.
  - United China Relief
    Subsequently United Service to China. Correspondence (including Henry R. Luce, Charles Edison, and Walter McConaughy), newsletters, reports, clippings, flyers, memoranda, and minutes.
    - 1941-1946 (Box-folder 192: 4)
    - 1947-1951 (Box-folder 193: 1)
  - United Nations
    - General, 1949-1972 (Box-folder 193: 2-4)
      Notes, by-laws, pamphlets, clippings, statements, printed articles, press releases, resolutions, reports, letters, and newsletters.
    - Correspondence, 1948-1971 (Box-folder 193: 5)
      Includes George Bush.
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 193: 6)
      Reports, notes, speech, biographical material, newsletters, and correspondence. Includes material relating to communist influence.
  - United States, relations with
    - General
      Pamphlets, newsletters, clippings, correspondence (including Dwight Eisenhower and the State Department), resolutions, press releases, notes, memoranda, transcripts, newsletters, position statements, reports, abstracts, serial issues, speeches and statements (including Franklin D. Roosevelt, Harry S. Truman, Chiang Kai-shek, John Foster Dulles, John F. Kennedy, Adlai Stevenson, Stanley Hornbeck, Henry Kissinger, Robert Dole, Barry Goldwater, Roscoe Pound, Claire Chennault, Millard Tydings, John D. Lodge, Owen Brewster, Richard Cardinal Cushing, Ernest Hollings, and James C.H. Shen), and printed articles (including Max Eastman, J.K. Fairbank, Clare Boothe Luce, Alfred Kohlberg, Pearl S. Buck, Stanley Hornbeck, Chester Bowles, William Bullitt, Walter McConaughy, George Sokolsky, Herbert Welch, and Roscoe Pound). Includes a U.S. Army report, a memorandum from Frank Price to George Marshall, and material relating to the issues of recognition of communist China, its admission to the UN, the Korean war, and the Geneva convention.
      - Undated (Box-folder 194: 1)
      - 1943-1953 (Box-folder 194: 2-7)
      - 1954-1969 (Box-folder 195: 1-5)
      - 1970-1980 (Box-folder 196: 1-4)
    - Aid
      - General
        Clippings, memoranda (including John S. Service to Joseph Stilwell), transcripts, correspondence (including A.C. Wedemeyer, Robert Lovett, and Kenneth Royall), reports (including the ICA, Raymond Moyer, and William Bullitt), newsletters, press releases, notes (relating to meetings with Robert Lovett and Arthur Vandenberg, and Madame Chiang), petition, pamphlets, speeches and statements (including Alfred Kohlberg, William Bullitt, Harry S. Truman, A.C. Wedemeyer, George Marshall, Styles Bridges, H.H. K'ung, and Ernest Moy), and articles (including Stanley Hornbeck and Claire Chennault). See also: CONGRESSIONAL FILE/Foreign Aid/Economic Assistance acts.
        - 1944-1947 (Box-folder 196: 5-6)
        - 1948-1950 (Box-folder 197: 1-4)
        - 1950-1954 (Box-folder 198: 1)
      - Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction, 1947-1967 (Box-folder 198: 2)
        Reports, memoranda, budgets, pamphlets, newsletter, notes, press releases, correspondence (including the ECA, Harlan Cleveland, Raymond Moyer and John Earl Baker), and printed articles (including William O. Douglas and Pearl Buck).
    - Chennault, Claire, 1944-1952 (Box-folder 198: 3)
      Reports, printed articles, statements, clippings, and notes.
    - China Lobby
      See also: American China Policy Association and CORRESPONDENCE FILE/Kohlberg, Alfred.
      - General, 1948-1977 (Box-folder 198: 4)
        Pamphlets, speeches, clippings, printed articles, serial issues, and a hearing transcript.
      - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 198: 5)
        Includes an unsent letter to the editor of the New York Times by Dr. Judd.
    - Hurley, Patrick, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 198: 6)
      Statements, correspondence, and clippings.
    - Loyalty-security issues, 1942-1974 (Box-folder 199: 1-2)
      Clippings, printed articles, speeches, correspondence, newsletters, reports, notes, serial issue, memorandum, transcript, and a book, The China Story, by Freda Utley, with annotations by Dr. Judd. Relates to alleged subversion of U.S. policy toward China. See also: State Department, Communist Party, U.S.A., and the Institute of Pacific Relations.
    - MacArthur, Douglas, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 199: 3)
    - Marshall, George C., 1947-1974 (Box-folder 199: 4)
      Questions and a transcript relating to congressional testimony by General Marshall, statements (including Joseph McCarthy), memorandum, (meeting?) notes, clippings, excerpts from material by Albert Wedemeyer, a letter, and printed articles (including Freda Utley).
    - State Department
      - General, 1943-1968 (Box-folder 199: 5)
        Clippings, correspondence (including Dean Rusk and Dean Acheson), and memoranda of conversations, including John Foster Dulles.
      - Acheson, Dean, 1949-1983 (Box-folder 199: 6)
        Clippings, correspondence, reports, press releases, speeches and statements, resolutions, notes, newsletter, and a petition.
      - Jessup, Philip C., 1949-1950 (Box-folder 199: 7)
        Clippings and a statement.
      - Lattimore, Owen, 1942-1955 (Box-folder 200: 1)
        Memorandum, book review, printed articles, serial issue, speeches and statements, notes, correspondence, and a flyer. Includes material relating to Chinese personnel employed by the Office of War Information.
      - Service, John Stewart, 1950-1973 (Box-folder 200: 2)
        Clippings, newsletter, printed article, and a meeting announcement.
      - Stuart, J. Leighton, 1947-1954 (Box-folder 200: 3)
        Statement, clipping, and book review.
      - United States Information Service, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 200: 4)
        Primarily correspondence with James Dyke van Putten relating to agency operation and conditions in Peiping.
      - Vincent, John Carter, 1947-1979 (Box-folder 200: 5)
        Notes, clippings, newsletters, and a printed article.
      - 1949 White Paper on U.S.-Chinese Relations
        - General, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 200: 6)
          Memoranda, reports, letters, newsletters, press releases, statements (including Dean Acheson and Patrick Hurley), clippings, and resolutions. Includes charges of omissions in the report by Dr. Judd.
        - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 200: 7)
          Includes Frederick McKee, Charles Cooke, Hamilton Fish, and Alfred Kohlberg.
    - Taiwan, relations with
      Correspondence (including Sherman Adams, John Foster Dulles, and Christopher Emmet), newsletters, press releases, clippings, notes, reports, printed material, speeches and statements (including Harry S. Truman, John Foster Dulles, Averell Harriman, George K.C. Yeh, Walter P. McConaughy, John Davis Lodge, Jesse Helms, and James C.H. Shen), and meeting notes (including V.K.W. Koo). Includes material relating to Quemoy and Matsu, the Formosa Resolution, foreign aid, recognition of the People's Republic of China, and anti-American riots.
      - 1949-1957 (Box-folder 200: 8)
      - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 201: 1-3)
    - Trade, 1953-1979 (Box-folder 201: 4)
      Speeches (including Strom Thurmond and Robert Byrd), printed articles, advertisements, clippings, and form letters.
    - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1946-1984 (Box-folder 201: 5)
      Correspondence, meeting notes, reports, newsletters, speeches and statements, and clippings.
  - World War II, 1938-1972 (Box-folder 201: 6)
    Clippings, correspondence, printed articles (including Pearl Buck), newsletters, reports, press releases, and a letter to the editor by Peter Pee. Includes material relating to the U.S. military in post-war China and the Communist Party.
- POLITICAL FILE, 1942-1983 (Box 202-217)
  Newsletters, speeches and statements, correspondence, biographical material, voting records, pamphlets, leaflets, campaign material, clippings, position statements and platforms, memoranda, questionnaires, financial material, reports, resolutions, form letters, press releases, notes, and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General, 1945-1980 (Box-folder 202: 1)
    Printed material, newsletters, speeches, and correspondence. Includes material relating to politics and government, the Democratic Party, George Romney, and John Anderson. Some individual Republican politicians are included in this series; material on presidents, vice presidents, and most Democrats is located in the SUBJECT FILE.
  - Congressional campaigns (Walter H. Judd)
    - General, circa 1948-1964 (Box-folder 202: 2)
      Printed material, draft newsletter, biographical sketch, notes, and campaign material.
    - Correspondence
      Includes material relating to local, regional, and national campaigns, and presidential administrations.
      - 1945-1958 (Box-folder 202: 3-9)
      - 1959-1972 (Box-folder 203: 1-2)
    - 1942 campaign (Box-folder 203: 3)
      Correspondence, campaign material, clippings, flyers, vote counts, form letters, pamphlets, leaflets, and miscellany. Includes a narrative describing Dr. Judd's decision to run for office.
    - 1944 campaign, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 203: 4-5)
      Correspondence (including Wendell Willkie, Thomas Dewey, and John Foster Dulles), speeches and statements, reports, lists, voting records, position statements, pamphlets, clippings, form letters, campaign material, statutes, memorandum, and miscellany.
    - 1946 campaign, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 204: 1-3)
      Correspondence, clippings, questionnaires, campaign material, voting records, lists, vote counts, pamphlets, leaflets, and form letters.
    - 1948 campaign, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 204: 4-5)
      Correspondence (including Gerald R. Ford), statements, form letters, questionnaires, campaign material, clippings, newsletters, financial material, and miscellany.
    - 1950 campaign, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 205: 1-4)
      Correspondence, campaign material, speeches and statements, clippings, form letters, voting records, position papers, and miscellany.
    - 1952 campaign (Box-folder 206: 1-2)
      Correspondence, voting records, questionnaires, campaign material, financial material, vote counts, lists, form letters, clippings, and miscellany.
    - 1954 campaign, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 207: 1-3, Box-folder 206: 3-4)
      Correspondence (including Dwight Eisenhower), statements, reports, financial material, clippings, press releases, circulars, lists, campaign material, questionnaires, and voting records.
    - 1956 campaign, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 208: 1-3, Box-folder 207: 4)
      Correspondence (including Dwight Eisenhower and Thomas Dodd), report, campaign material, flyers, memoranda, opinion survey, clippings, notes, lists, and voting records.
    - 1958 campaign, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 209: 1-4)
      Correspondence, lists, report, campaign material, statements, letter, flyers, minutes, clippings, vote counts, and miscellany.
    - 1960 campaign, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 210: 1-2)
      Correspondence, clippings, and campaign material.
    - 1962 campaign, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 210: 3-4)
      Campaign material, clippings, flyers, pamphlets, reports, newsletters, notes, statements, and press releases.
  - Goldwater, Barry, 1960-1975 (Box-folder 210: 5)
    Speeches, notes, newsletters, campaign material, notes, biographical material, and form letters.
  - Minnesota politics, 1945-1974 (Box-folder 210: 6)
    Clippings, campaign material, speeches (including Lauris Norstad), and correspondence. Includes material relating to the Democratic-Farmer-Labor Party.
  - Presidential campaigns
    - 1944 campaign, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 211: 1)
      Printed material, reports, speeches (including Thomas Dewey and Joseph Ball), platforms, clippings, miscellany, and form letters.
    - 1948 campaign
      - General, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 211: 2)
        Correspondence (including Thomas Dewey and J.F. Dulles), speeches and statements (including Joseph Martin, Harry S. Truman, and Clare Boothe Luce), newsletters, notes, press release, clippings, and campaign material. See also: Stassen, Harold.
      - Republican convention, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 211: 3)
        Correspondence (including Herbert Brownell, Jr., and Warren Burger), speeches, platform, broadcast transcript, statistical report, and miscellany.
    - 1952 campaign
      - General, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 211: 4-5)
        Speeches and statements (including Robert Taft, Dwight Eisenhower, Harry Truman, John McCormack, Albert Wedemeyer, and Richard Nixon), printed articles, memoranda, clippings, notes, biographical material, press releases, leaflets, position statements, campaign material, bulletins, and voter surveys. Includes material relating to Thomas Dewey, Robert Taft, and Dwight Eisenhower.
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1951-1974 (Box-folder 212: 1-3)
        - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1952 (Box-folder 212: 4)
          Includes correspondence with staff members, a copy of a letter from Milton Eisenhower to his brother, and a memorandum from Dr. Judd to Dwight Eisenhower.
      - Republican convention, 1952 (Box-folder 212: 5)
        Correspondence, platforms, printed material, campaign material, speeches and statements (including Douglas MacArthur), and miscellany. Includes material relating to Robert Taft.
    - 1956 campaign, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 213: 1)
      Correspondence (including a letter to Christian Herter), clippings, platforms, and campaign material.
    - 1960 campaign
      See also: SUBJECT FILE/Kennedy, John F.
      - General, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 213: 2)
        Correspondence, speeches (including Dwight Eisenhower and Richard Nixon), newsletter, and clippings. Includes material relating to allegations by Dr. Judd of electoral fraud.
      - Republican convention, 1960 (Box-folder 213: 3)
        Speeches (including Dwight Eisenhower, Herbert Hoover, and Barry Goldwater), correspondence, delegate lists, miscellany, and clippings. Includes material relating to Henry Cabot Lodge and the possiblity of Dr. Judd being picked as the vice presidential candidate.
    - 1964 campaign (Box-folder 213: 4)
      Platform, report, printed material, campaign material, and speeches and statements (including Richard Nixon, Strom Thurmond and George Romney). Includes material relating to William Scranton and Henry Cabot Lodge. See also: Goldwater, Barry.
    - 1968 campaign, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 213: 5)
      Correspondence (including Maurice Stans, Dwight Eisenhower and Anna Chennault), newsletters, clippings, a position paper on NATO, a report by John Tower on Southeast Asia, speeches (Richard Nixon), and miscellany. See also: SUBJECT FILE/Nixon, Richard M.
  - Republican Party
    - General, 1932-1984 (Box-folder 214: 1-4)
      Correspondence (including Karl Mundt, John Tower, and various Republican candidates), reports, position statements, newsletters, printed material, speeches and statements (including Clare Boothe Luce, Abraham Lincoln, and Melvin Laird), notes, flyers, and resolutions.
    - Congressional Republicans, 1942-1970 (Box-folder 214: 5)
      Includes the National Congressional Committee. Policy statements and platforms, reports, pamphlets, clippings, and correspondence.
    - Hennepin County Committee, 1946-1962 (Box-folder 215: 1)
      Correspondence, circulars, memoranda, newsletters, and lists. Includes some state committee material.
    - Republican Citizens Committee, Critical Issues Council, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 215: 2)
      Clippings, correspondence (including Milton Eisenhower), memoranda, minutes, pamphlets, reports, and a program proposal.
    - Republican National Committee
      - General, 1945-1975 (Box-folder 215: 3-5)
        Correspondence (including Rogers Morton and Herbert Brownell, Jr.), lists, reports, biographical material, newsletters, press releases, campaign material, and miscellany.
      - Finance Committee, 1952-1968 (Box-folder 215: 6)
        Correspondence (including Lucius Clay), and bulletins.
      - Policy Committee, 1959-1968 (Box-folder 216: 1)
        Reports, correspondence (including Robert Hill), pamphlets, speeches, draft resolution, and press releases. Primarily relates to foreign relations task forces, including one established to advise Barry Goldwater on Asia and Vietnam.
    - Republican workshops, 1945-1971 (Box-folder 216: 2-3)
      Includes National Council of Republican Workshops. Correspondence, newsletters, by-laws, and miscellany.
  - Stassen, Harold, 1943-1960 (Box-folder 217: 1-2, Box-folder 216: 4)
    Speeches, printed articles, flyers, campaign material, clippings, circulars, and correspondence (including Harold Stassen and others).
  - Taft, Robert A., 1952-1983 (Box-folder 217: 3)
    Correspondence, flyer, speeches, clippings, and miscellany. Primarily relates to the Robert Taft Institute of Government. See also: Presidential campaigns/1952 campaign.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1928-1984 (Box 217-256)
  Correspondence, reports, printed articles, clippings, newsletters, leaflets, serial issues, maps, notes, speeches and statements, memoranda, agendas and minutes, lists, resolutions, press releases, financial material, form letters, bibliographies, pamphlets, flyers, serial issues, transcripts, policy statements, interviews, book reviews, chronologies, conference material, by-laws, and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General, 1955-1980 (Box-folder 217: 4)
    Speeches and statements, printed articles, newsletters, and clippings.
  - Accuracy in Media, 1970-1984 (Box-folder 217: 5)
    Proposal, reports, correspondence (including Reed Irvine), clippings, bulletins, press releases, and miscellany.
  - Afghanistan, 1970-1982 (Box-folder 217: 6)
    Letter and newsletters.
  - Africa
    - General, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 217: 7)
      Clippings, pamphlets, printed articles, an interview (H. Kamuzu Banda, President of Malawi), correspondence (including Thomas Dodd to Dean Rusk), leaflets, serial issues, map, newsletters, and notes. Includes material relating to Nigeria, Biafra, Angola, Ghana, race relations, and the Organization of African Unity.
    - American-African Affairs Association, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 218: 1)
      Form letters, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and miscellany.
    - South Africa and Rhodesia, 1964-1982 (Box-folder 218: 2)
      Clippings, newsletters, statements, correspondence and a pamphlet. Includes material relating to elections and boycotts.
  - Agnew, Spiro, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 218: 3)
    Clippings, statements, and a newsletter.
  - American Citizenship Center, 1969-1984 (Box-folder 218: 4-5)
    Correspondence, list, minutes, fundraising material, reports, printed material, and form letters.
  - American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 218: 6)
    Subsequently the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies. Program statements, printed material, correspondence (including Chiang Soong Mei-ling and J. Leighton Stuart), minutes, lists, notes, and form letters.
  - American Council for World Freedom (ACWF), 1970-1980 (Box-folder 219: 1-2, Box-folder 218: 7)
    Correspondence (including Lee Edwards and Fred Schlafly), financial material, printed material, agenda and minutes, memoranda, press releases, and miscellany. See also: Communism and anti-communism/World Anti-Communist League.
  - American Friends of Captive Nations, 1953-1968 (Box-folder 219: 3-4)
    Correspondence (including Christopher Emmet), minutes, memoranda, reports, resolution, conference material, clippings, notes, and form letters. Includes material relating to Hungary and the Berlin crisis.
  - American Heritage Center, 1970-1982 (Box-folder 220: 1)
  - American Peace Society, 1960-1979 (Box-folder 220: 2)
    Correspondence, agenda and minutes, financial material, draft policy statement.
  - American Research Hospital for Children, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 220: 3)